so let's discuss the solution to our
amal's law quiz the program has 50
billion instructions this is how many
instructions according to the
instruction count are integer 40%
branches are 1/5 of our instructions
stores are 10% and so on and this is the
original CPI and the Improvement we have
is that the branches have improved from
4 to 2 CPI if we try to use am's law we
might do something like this this
overall speed up is 1 over 1 minus
fraction enhanced the fraction enhanced
is 20% so it would be 0.8 is the 1 minus
that plus 0.2 is the fraction enhanced
divided by the speed up is two so this
would be 1 over 0.9 which would be 1.111
and if you did this you would be
horribly horribly wrong the reason this
is wrong is that the fraction enhanced
is not as a percent
of the overall execution time before the
Improvement we said this is how many
instructions are enhanced so branches
are 20% of the instruction count but we
don't know what percentage of execution
time was spent on branches and execution
time is what we are interested here so
the one of the possible correct
Solutions here is simply to do the
following using the iron law we can
compute that for 40% of our instructions
we were getting a CPI of one for 20% of
the instructions we are getting a CPI of
4 for 30% of the instructions we're
getting a CP of two and for 10% of our
instructions we were getting a CP of
three multiply that by our 50 billion
and multiply that by 1 over 2 billion
which is the 2 GHz so this would be the
execution time before the enhancement
after the enhancement we would be having
the same thing except there would be a
two here and if you do that the answer
will be
1.24 in order to be able to use amd's
law what we have to figure out is of
this execution time what fraction were
the branches and if we did that we would
be able to plug that number here and
here as the fraction enhanced and get
the correct answer here so again do not
use something other than the fraction of
execution time as your fraction enhanced
because you will not get the correct
answer